A Guide to the Webb-Prentis Family Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Webb-Prentis Family Papers 1770-1908
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4136
ca. 10,000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 14 November 1972
Scope and Content Information
Family papers of the Webb-Prentis families and numerous other Virginians including: correspondence, business papers, legal papers, Nansemond County, Va. papers, genealogy, miscellaneous papers, bound volumes including accounts, legal, medical, memorandum, drawings, oversize items, and lecture notebooks and transcripts.
The collection has sections devoted to Joseph Prentis, Sr. and family; Joseph Prentis, Jr. and family; Prentis family; Allen and Darden Families and miscellaneous correspondence.
The collection contains a document appointing Joseph Prentis as Inspector of Revenue for the Port of Suffolk, 1825 March 17, signed by John Quincy Adams.
Also of interest is a floor plan, 1800 Nov. 12, for "Chaumiere des Praries" a log house in Jessamine County, Ky.
Container List
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
  - A. Joseph Prentis, Sr. and Family
    - Leroy Anderson to Joseph Prentis and Joseph, Jr., 1796-1822 (Box Box 1)
    - Robert Anderson to Joseph Prentis and Joseph, Jr., 1801-1832 (Box Box 1)
    - Robert Andrews to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805-1806 (Box Box 1)
    - Ja. C. Anthony to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1803-1805 (Box Box 1)
    - Philip Barraud to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1801-1808 (Box Box 1)
    - Burwell Bassett to Joseph Prentis and Joseph, Jr., 1805-1825 (Box Box 1)
    - William Browne to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1800 (Box Box 1)
    - Sally Byrd to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1807 (Box Box 1)
    - William H. Cabell to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1808 (Box Box 1)
    - Robert Carter II to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1788-1789 (Box Box 1)
    - J. A. Chevallie to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805 (Box Box 1)
    - Adam Craig to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805-1807 (Box Box 1)
    - Joseph Davenport to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1784-1787 (Box Box 1)
    - Benjamin Day to Robert and Joseph Prentis, 1783-1802 (Box Box 1)
    - Peter Robert Deneufville to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1801-1809 (Box Box 1)
    - Augustine Denos to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1804-1805 (Box Box 1)
    - John Driver to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1779-1810 (Box Box 1)
    - Josiah Fox to Burwell Bassett and Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1807-1808 (Box Box 1)
    - Alexander D. Galt to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1802-1823 (Box Box 1)
    - Robert Greenhow to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1789-1809 (Box Box 1)
    - Walter Herran to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805 (Box Box 1)
    - George Jackson to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1795-1816 (Box Box 1)
    - Jennings and Roddey to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1808 (Box Box 1)
    - Miles King to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805-1808 (Box Box 1)
    - B. Lee to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1807 (Box Box 1)
    - Henry G. Letuz to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805 (Box Box 1)
    - Elizabeth Bowdoin McCroskey to Joseph Prentis, Sr.; and copy of Will, 1803, 1802-1807 (Box Box 1)
    - James Madison to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1807 (Box Box 1)
    - James Madison, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1799-1802 (Box Box 1)
    - Andrew Marr to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1788-1790, 1809 (Box Box 1)
    - David Meade to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1796-1808 (Box Box 1)
    - Floor plan of "Chaumiere des Praries" a log house in Jessamine County, Ky., 1800 Nov. 12 (Box Box 1)
    - David Meade, Jr. to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1804-1812 (Box Box 1)
    - Hugh K. Meade to Joseph Prentis, Sr. and Elizabeth Prentis, 1807-1809 (Box Box 1)
    - Richard E. Meade to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1809, 1829-1832 (Box Box 1)
    - Sarah Waters Meade to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1796-1806 (Box Box 1)
    - James Monroe to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1808, 1821 (Box Box 1)
    - Alexander Moseley to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1784-1787 (Box Box 2)
    - Thomas Newton, Sr. to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1785-1786 (Box Box 2)
    - Alice Pagaud to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1797-1798 (Box Box 2)
    - Samuel L. Pleasants, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1801-1809 (Box Box 2)
    - Eliza B. Prentis Vickery Pollard to Joseph Prentis, Joseph Prentis, Jr., and Catherine Prentis, 1805-1810 (Box Box 2)
    - John B. Prentis to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1807 (Box Box 2)
    - John B. Prentis to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1808-1819 (Box Box 2)
    - Joseph Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1796-1804 (Box Box 2)
    - Joseph Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1807-1809 (Box Box 2)
    - Joseph Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1806 (Box Box 2)
    - Joseph Prentis, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Mary Prentis, Susan C. Riddick Prentis, Richard W. Riddick, and various clients, 1809-1821 (Box Box 2)
    - Margaret Bowdoin Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1801 (Box Box 2)
    - Robert Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1783-1805 (Box Box 2)
    - William Prentis to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1784-1818 (Box Box 3)
    - Edmund Randolph to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1775-1808 (Box Box 3)
    - Duncan Rose to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1779-1801 (Box Box 3)
    - John M. St. George to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1803-1816 (Box Box 3)
    - James Sample to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1808, 1826 (Box Box 3)
    - Robert Saunders to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1798-1814 (Box Box 3)
    - George & Thomas Littleton Savage to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1791-1806 (Box Box 3)
    - Hamilton Shields to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1806-1825 (Box Box 3)
    - Thomas Shrimpton to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1775-1783 (Box Box 3)
    - Charles E. and Nathan A. Smith to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805-1809 (Box Box 3)
    - General John Smith to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1807-1808 (Box Box 3)
    - Thorougood Smith to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1786-1790 (Box Box 3)
    - Turner Southall to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1785 (Box Box 3)
    - Alexander Speirs and Co. to John Prentis, 1775 (Box Box 3)
    - W. Stark to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1785 (Box Box 3)
    - John Stringer to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1784 (Box Box 3)
    - Thomas Swepson to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1809-1820 (Box Box 3)
    - Henry Tazewell to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1783-1798 (Box Box 3)
    - St. George Tucker to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1808 (Box Box 3)
    - John Tyler to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805-1809 (Box Box 3)
    - John Wickham to Joseph Prentis [and Joseph Prentis, Jr. ], 1807-1822 (Box Box 3)
    - Thomas Wilson to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1808 (Box Box 3)
    - Wilson & Swann to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1799-1800 (Box Box 3)
    - William Wiseham to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1803-1805 (Box Box 3)
    - Richard Yarborough to Joseph Prentis, Sr., 1805-1806 (Box Box 3)
  - B. Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Family
    - Albert Allmand to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1815-1826 (Box Box 4)
    - Harrison Allmand to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811-1816 (Box Box 4)
    - John Allmand to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1832-1837 (Box Box 4)
    - Joseph T. Allyn to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and S. Hartshorne, 1830 (Box Box 4)
    - John A. Anderson to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1846-1848 (Box Box 4)
    - Anderson & Goodridge to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1834 (Box Box 4)
    - Thomas F. Andrews to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1850 (Box Box 4)
    - Robert Archer to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1818-1828 (Box Box 4)
    - James Armstrong, Jr. to "Friend Joe" [ Joseph Prentis, III ], 1865 (Box Box 4)
    - Archibald Atkinson to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and M[ ] Webb, 1823-1866 (Box Box 4)
    - Benjamin B. Baker to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1820-1834 (Box Box 4)
    - John B. Baker to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1814, 1832 (Box Box 4)
    - Joseph B. Baker to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811-1814 (Box Box 4)
    - Richard H. Baker to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1822-1850 (Box Box 4)
    - Kenar Ballard to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1818 (Box Box 4)
    - William T. Banks to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817-1849 (Box Box 4)
    - John Barber to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1807-1811 (Box Box 4)
    - D. C. & Otway B. Barraud to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1838, 1846 (Box Box 4)
    - Lelia A. Barraud Baker to Margaret S. and Susan Prentis (Box Box 4)
    - Ann Barron to Margaret Susan Prentis Webb, 1832-1836 (Box Box 4)
    - Thomas M. Bayly to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1810-1811 (Box Box 4)
    - Thomas Bennett to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1815-1823 (Box Box 4)
    - John B. Benton to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825-1843 (Box Box 4)
    - Caleb Bonsal to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1840 (Box Box 4)
    - Roscius C. and Thomas Borland to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1814-1829 (Box Box 4)
    - Nathaniel Bousch to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1818 (Box Box 5)
    - John T. Bowdoin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1807-1818 (Box Box 5)
    - Peter Bowdoin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1803-1825; (2 folders) (Box Box 5)
    - Peter S. Bowdoin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825-1838 (Box Box 5)
    - Preeson Bowdoin I to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1784-1785 (Box Box 5)
    - Susan Bowdoin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1801-1831 (Box Box 5)
    - Susan Bowdoin to Margaret Susan (niece) and Joseph (nephew) Prentis, 1829-1832 (Box Box 5)
    - Fanny Boykin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1825 (Box Box 5)
    - Richard H. Bradford to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811, 1830 (Box Box 5)
    - F. Brette and Company to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1832 (Box Box 5)
    - Thomas G. Broughton to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1847 (Box Box 5)
    - Benjamin Brown to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1804 (Box Box 5)
    - William Brown to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1828-1831 (Box Box 5)
    - James Browne, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1837-1840 (Box Box 5)
    - John Browne to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1800-1816 (Box Box 5)
    - William Browne, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1804-1829 (Box Box 5)
    - John B. Butler to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1848 (Box Box 5)
    - Richard Willing Byrd to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1806-1820 (Box Box 5)
    - James Cabaniss to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1826-1834 (Box Box 5)
    - A & W Caldwell to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824 (Box Box 5)
    - Capt. Edward Chamberlain to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817-1828 (Box Box 5)
    - Mary Anne Prentis Chamberlain to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1827 (Box Box 6)
    - John R. Chambliss to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1842 (Box Box 6)
    - John A. Chandler to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1828-1848 (Box Box 6)
    - Henry Christian to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1801 (Box Box 6)
    - John Cocke to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1832, 1835 (Box Box 6)
    - Richard H. Cocke to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824-1830 (Box Box 6)
    - Samuel B. Cocke to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1834 (Box Box 6)
    - Gen. John C. Cohoon to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1807-1821 (Box Box 6)
    - John C. Cohoon, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1815-1850 (Box Box 6)
    - Josiah Cole to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811-1812 (Box Box 6)
    - William Coleman to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1812, 1815 (Box Box 6)
    - Bettie F. Coleston to Dr. [Robert Henning] Webb, n.d. (Box Box 6)
    - Jeannie Colston to Joseph Prentis Webb, n.d. (Box Box 6)
    - Lucy Colston to J[oseph] P[rentis] Webb, n.d. (Box Box 6)
    - Mordecai Cooke, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1817 (Box Box 6)
    - John B. Cooper to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816-1829 (Box Box 6)
    - Samuel and Harriett Corbell to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1819-1846 (Box Box 6)
    - Willis Cowling to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1812-1826 (Box Box 6)
    - Leopold C. P. Cowper to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1837-1848 (Box Box 6)
    - William Cowper to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1810-1831 (Box Box 6)
    - Robert Creighton to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816 (Box Box 6)
    - Hardy Crop to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1840 (Box Box 6)
    - William E. Cunningham to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1848 (Box Box 6)
    - William P. Custis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823 (Box Box 6)
    - H. K. and John H. Darden to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1826-1849 (Box Box 6)
    - Soloman Daughtry to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1826 (Box Box 6)
    - Julia Davidson to [Susan C. Riddick] Prentis, 1860 (Box Box 6)
    - Augustine Davis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824-1825 (Box Box 6)
    - John A. G. Davis: Grade Reports for Peter B. and Robert Prentis, 1839-1840 (Box Box 6)
    - John Davis Day to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1849 (Box Box 6)
    - William H. Day to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1844 (Box Box 6)
    - Matthew Denson to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1832-1842 (Box Box 6)
    - J. Dickinson to Margaret Susan Prentis, 1829-1830 (Box Box 6)
    - Gabriel P. Dissoway to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1833-1844 (Box Box 6)
    - William G. Driver to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1819-1834 (Box Box 6)
    - James Dyker to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817-1818 (Box Box 6)
    - Littleton R. Edwards to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1842-1848 (Box Box 6)
    - Thomas Edwards to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824-1825 (Box Box 6)
    - John C. Ehringhaus to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1835 (Box Box 7)
    - Hamlin L. Eppes to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1830 (Box Box 7)
    - John Eyre to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816 (Box Box 7)
    - Thomas Fanning to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824 (Box Box 7)
    - James Fassitt & Company to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1835 (Box Box 7)
    - John Faulcon to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1810, 1821 (Box Box 7)
    - William Fenwick to Joseph Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1798, 1820-1821 (Box Box 7)
    - Crawley Finney to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1830-1850 (Box Box 7)
    - Robert Henning Fisher to Joseph Prentis, Jr.; AMsS, "The Story of Adelaide Sceiller;" and, Last Will and Testament, 1793, 1811-1814 (Box Box 7)
    - John K. Floyd to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1822-1827 (Box Box 7)
    - Owen R. Flynn to Richard M. Riddick and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1847-1850 (Box Box 7)
    - Edward Frith to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1814-1823 (Box Box 7)
    - Alexander Galt to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1815-1838 (Box Box 7)
    - William T. Galt to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1798-1819 (Box Box 7)
    - James Gardner III to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817 (Box Box 7)
    - John Gaskin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1842 (Box Box 7)
    - Alfred M. Gatlin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1835 (Box Box 7)
    - Jonathan L. Godwin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1832-1834 (Box Box 7)
    - Mills Godwin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1820-1823 (Box Box 7)
    - Thomas Godwin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1830 (Box Box 7)
    - Thomas Henry Pitt Godwin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1820-1840 (Box Box 7)
    - William B. Godwin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1818-1833 (Box Box 7)
    - William C. Godwin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1834 (Box Box 7)
    - Jethro D. Goodman to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1806 (Box Box 7)
    - G. Grainger to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811 (Box Box 7)
    - John Gray to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1825 (Box Box 7)
    - Charles E. Hall to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1831 (Box Box 7)
    - Gavin Hamilton to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1822-1823 (Box Box 7)
    - John Hamilton to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805 (Box Box 7)
    - Harris & Snead to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825 (Box Box 7)
    - Hiram Harris to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Mr. Atkinson, 1833 (Box Box 7)
    - Gessner Harrison: Grade Reports for Robert R. and Peter B. Prentis, 1838-1839 (Box Box 7)
    - William H. Harrison to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1836-1837 (Box Box 7)
    - Kedar Hill to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1839 (Box Box 7)
    - George A. Hitchcock to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1822-1823 (Box Box 7)
    - William D. Hodges to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1833-1840 (Box Box 7)
    - Joseph Holladay to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1838 (Box Box 7)
    - Moses Holmes to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1830-1832 (Box Box 7)
    - William C. Holt to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1804, 1821-1830 (Box Box 7)
    - Joseph Hook to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816-1865 (Box Box 7)
    - Edward R. Hunter to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1813-1850 (Box Box 7)
    - Edward Jenkins to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816 (Box Box 7)
    - Johnson & Fingley to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1830 (Box Box 8)
    - James Johnson to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1813-1823 (Box Box 8)
    - James Jones to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1831-1840 (Box Box 8)
    - Joseph G. Jordan to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1832 (Box Box 8)
    - Merit Jordan to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817-1845 (Box Box 8)
    - William H. Jordan to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1845 (Box Box 8)
    - Thomas R. Joynes to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1831 (Box Box 8)
    - Jacob Keeling to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1815-1850 (Box Box 8)
    - Jacob Keeling to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1834 (Box Box 8)
    - Hutchinson Kellam to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1827-1828 (Box Box 8)
    - Hugh H. Kelly to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1837-1848 (Box Box 8)
    - George T. Kennon to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825 (Box Box 8)
    - Ann Newton Kilby to Margaret Susan Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1831 (Box Box 8)
    - John R. Kilby to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1838-1849 (Box Box 8)
    - John T. Kilby I to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817-1829 (Box Box 8)
    - John T. Kilby II to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1849 (Box Box 8)
    - Missouri A. J. Kilby to Margaret Susan Prentis, 1833 (Box Box 8)
    - Thomas J. Kilby to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1849 (Box Box 8)
    - William Langhorne to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1819-1820 (Box Box 8)
    - Edwin Lee to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823 (Box Box 8)
    - Lawrence Lewis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1839 (Box Box 8)
    - Lawrence Lewis, II to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1840-1844 (Box Box 8)
    - Mary A. Lewis to Mariana Saunders Prentis, 1850-1851 (Box Box 8)
    - Robert Lively to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1827-1830 (Box Box 8)
    - George Loyall to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1831-1834 (Box Box 8)
    - Daniel Lyon & Co. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1826 (Box Box 8)
    - Robert McCandlish to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1826 (Box Box 8)
    - William McCandlish to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1807 (Box Box 8)
    - E. B. McGuire to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1846 (Box Box 8)
    - George McIntosh to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1818-1822 (Box Box 8)
    - William K. McKinder to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811-1834 (Box Box 8)
    - A. McRoberts to James Watt, Jr., 1788 (Box Box 8)
    - Nathaniel Magill to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1805-1815 (Box Box 8)
    - Charles King Mallory to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1800-1817 (Box Box 8)
    - John Y. and M. A. Mason to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1837-1845 (Box Box 8)
    - David Meade to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1818 (Box Box 8)
    - David Meade to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1822-1828 (Box Box 8)
    - Nelson Millar to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824-1825 (Box Box 8)
    - John F. Miller to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1808 (Box Box 8)
    - John R. Moderno to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825-1826 (Box Box 8)
    - Jacob Mordecai to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1810 (Box Box 8)
    - Samuel Moseley to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816 (Box Box 8)
    - James Murdaugh to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1828 -1849 (Box Box 8)
    - Dr. John Murdaugh to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1809-1826 (Box Box 8)
    - Frederick Myers to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1830 (Box Box 8)
    - Nellie R. Nalle to [Joseph Prentis I] Webb, 1875-1876 (Box Box 8)
    - E. P. Nash & Co. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1831 (Box Box 8)
    - Judge William Nelson to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1808-1810 (Box Box 9)
    - Thomas Newton to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1810 -1826 (Box Box 9)
    - James H. Pagaud to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817-1823 (Box Box 9)
    - Julia F. Pagaud to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Susannah Radick, 1808 (Box Box 9)
    - Josiah C. Parker to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1834 (Box Box 9)
    - Edmund Pedin to Thomas Bennett and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816-1818 (Box Box 9)
    - John G. Pinner to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811-1830 (Box Box 9)
    - Benjamin Pollard to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1814-1850 (Box Box 9)
    - Ellen [Pollard] to "Cousin Margaret" [Prentis Webb], 1858-1864 (Box Box 9)
    - Eliza B. Prentis Vickery Pollard to Joseph Prentis, Jr., Doctor Robert H. Webb, and Margaret Prentis Webb, 1816-1832 (Box Box 9)
    - Eliza B. Prentis Vickery Pollard to Margaret Susan Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1833-1837 (Box Box 9)
    - Eliza B. Prentis Vickery Pollard to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Margaret Prentis Webb, 1838-1859 (Box Box 9)
    - William M. Poole to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1804-1810 (Box Box 9)
    - Catherine Prentis to Margaret S. Prentis and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1848 (Box Box 9)
    - James Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1814-1819 (Box Box 9)
    - John B. Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1822-1842 (Box Box 9)
    - John B. Prentis II to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Robert H. Webb, 1848-1860 (Box Box 9)
    - John Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824-1830 (Box Box 9)
    - Joseph Prentis, Jr. to Jospeh Prentis, Sr. and Susan L. Riddick, 1805-1808 (Box Box 10)
    - Joseph Prentis, Jr. to Susan C. Riddick Prentis, Margaret Susan Prentis, and Mary Anna Prentis, and various clients, 1822-1825 (Box Box 10)
    - Joseph Prentis, Jr. to Susan C. Riddick Prentis, Margaret Susan Prentis and Marianna Saunders Prentis, and various clients, 1826-1827 (Box Box 10)
    - Joseph Prentis, Jr. to Susan C. Riddick Prentis, Margaret Susan Prentis, and various clients, 1828-1829 (Box Box 10)
    - Peter Bowdoin Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1836-1863 (Box Box 10)
    - Joseph Prentis, Jr. to Susan C. Riddick Prentis, Margaret S. Prentis, Marianna Saunders Prentis, Doctor Robert H. Webb, and John B. Prentis, and various clients, 1830-1835 (Box Box 10)
    - Joseph Prentis, Jr. to Jacob Vickery and Margaret S. Prentis Webb, 1836-1851 (Box Box 10)
    - Joseph Prentis III to Margaret S. Prentis, Joseph Prentis, Jr., and Susan C. Prentis, 1826-1829 (Box Box 10)
    - Robert Riddick Prentis to Margaret S. Prentis Webb, Joseph Prentis, Jr., and Susan C. Riddick Prentis, 1835-1838 (Box Box 11)
    - Robert Riddick Prentis to Margaret S. Prentis Webb, Joseph Prentis, Jr., and Susan C. Riddick Prentis, 1839-1862 (Box Box 11)
    - Susan Caroline Riddick Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., and Margaret S. Prentis, 1823-1858, n.d. (Box Box 11)
    - Christopher and John C. Pryor to Joseph Prentis, Jr., and Samuel Vickery, 1828-1833 (Box Box 11)
    - Samuel T. Pulliam to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1826 (Box Box 11)
    - Richard Randolph to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825-1826 (Box Box 11)
    - James Rawlings to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816-1837 (Box Box 11)
    - James Ratcliff to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1804 (Box Box 11)
    - Ann [Riddick] to Joe [Joseph Prentis Webb], 1864 (Box Box 11)
    - Benjamin Riddick to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1829-1849 (Box Box 11)
    - Edward Riddick to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1806-1827 (Box Box 11)
    - Henry Riddick to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1817-1826 (Box Box 11)
    - Col. Josiah Riddick to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1806-1829 (Box Box 11)
    - Marianna S. Prentis Riddick to Susan C. Riddick Prentis, Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Margaret S. Prentis, 1826-1862 (Box Box 11)
    - Richard H. Riddick, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Marianna S. Riddick, 1830-1860 (Box Box 11)
    - Richard W. Riddick to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1818-1828 (Box Box 11)
    - Thomas F. Riddick to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1824 (Box Box 11)
    - John A. Roberts & Co. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825 (Box Box 11)
    - David Robertson to Robert Hines and Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1816-1821 (Box Box 11)
    - Joseph H. Robertson to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1830 (Box Box 11)
    - William G. Robertson to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1823-1826 (Box Box 11)
    - Merit M. Robinson to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1811-1815 (Box Box 11)
    - William Ruffin to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1810 (Box Box 11)
    - Col. John Rutherfoord to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1837 (Box Box 11)
    - Mary H. Saunders to Margaret Susan Prentis, 1822 (Box Box 12)
    - Robert Saunders, Jr. to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825-1851 (Box Box 12)
    - Robert Saunders to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1815-1828 (Box Box 12)
    - Dr. E. P. Scott to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1840 (Box Box 12)
    - Mrs. C. Sheddon and Margaret Susan Prentis to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1825-1827 (Box Box 12)
    - Thomas Shepherd to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1808-1810 (Box Box 12)
    - Thomas Swepson Shepherd to Joseph Prentis, Jr. and Mary Swepson Allen, 1834-1852 (Box Box 12)
    - William H. Shields and John Armistead to Joseph Prentis, Jr., 1833-1834 (Box Box 12)
    - "Ludy" Smith to Joseph P. Webb and "Cousin Margaret", 1871-1875 (Box Box 12)